So there I am on the look out,
当时我正在巡逻
when out of nowhere these high beams light up my rear view.
突然有人用远光灯晃我的后视镜
And then they hit me.
然后把我拦了下来
I'm illegally parked!
说我非法停车！
Another parking ticket?
又领到罚单了吧？
Better, the boot.
比那更厉害 一只靴子
Big metal tyre clamp, impossible to remove.
大大的金属轮胎夹 根本弄不掉
Bingo!
对头！
So the local police do their thing,
不过警方也是在照章办事
and I led them get all the way down the block.
我领着他们跑过整整一个街区
That's when I kick out my new shiny shoe and "bang!"
然后一脚踢掉了那只锃亮的靴子 “砰”的一声
New York's finests soil themselves.
纽约的警察太没面子了
You know me, Arcee
你是了解我的 阿尔茜
mess with Cliffjumper...
想跟我飞过山作对
And check at the horns.
先看看你那对牛角！
Not sure how that complies with Autobot rule No.1,
可这似乎违背了汽车人守则第一条：
keep a low profile.
保持低调
What can I say?
怎么说呢？
Patrolling for energon out here in Dullsville gets alone, so.
在这鸟不拉屎的地方搜索能量实在无聊
Almost makes me miss the Decepticons.
我都有点想念霸天虎了
Like Jasper Nevada has a party?
你是来内华达州的贾斯帕玩吗？
We're alone wherever we travel on this rock, Cliff.
这个星球上无论身处何处 我们都是孤立的 小飞
I'm getting a signal.
我收到一个信号
Need backup?
需要后援吗？
Do I ever need backup?
就凭我 需要后援吗？
I just found a whole lotta energon!
我刚发现了一大堆能量！
Decepticons!
霸天虎！
Arcee, about that backup...
阿尔茜 关于后援的问题…
Fair warning, boys.
听好了 小子们
I'll put a few dints in ya.
我给你们点颜色看看
Arcee to Optimus.
阿尔茜呼叫擎天柱
The Cons are back.
虎子们回来了
Cliff might be knee deep in scrap.
小飞处境非常危险
Understood.
明白
Ratchet, do you have Cliffjumper's coordinate?
救护车 你有飞过山的坐标吗？
I'm locked on his signal, Optimus.
我已经锁定了他的信号 擎天柱
But our team is scattered across time zones.
但我们的队员分散在不同的时区
Arcee, Bulkhead, Bumblebee,
阿尔茜 隔板 大黄蜂
rendezvous back at base and prepare to ground bridge.
在基地汇合 准备进入环陆桥
You want the horns?
喜欢我的角吗？
You got 'em.
让你们吃个够！
The energon is worthless to me now.
这里的能量已经没用了
Scream,
红蜘蛛
it's been a while.
久违了
So, where is your master?
我说 你的主子呢？
Never mind him!
少跟我提他！
I am my own master!
我就是自己的主子！
Any more questions?
还有问题吗？
Clean that up.
把它清理干净
An untapped energon deposit.
一个未开发的能量矿
What's left of it?
所剩无几了吧？
The first Decepticon activity in three years.
三年来霸天虎的首次行动
That we know of.
但愿如此
If they're scouting for energon,
如果他们真是在寻找能量
they maybe preparing for his return.
则可能是为他的回归做准备
No.
不
Ratchet, can you track his position?
救护车 你能追踪到他的方位吗？
No!
不！
Cliffjumper's life signal... just went offline.
飞过山的生命信号…刚刚消失了
Soundwave, what is it?
声波 怎么了？
"Like Jasper Nevada has a party?"
“你是来内华达州的贾斯帕玩吗？”
"We're alone wherever we travel on this rock, Cliff."
“这个星球上无论身处何处 我们都是孤立的 小飞”
The one called Arcee...
还有个叫阿尔茜的…
Why slay just one Autobot,
既然他们在明 我们在暗
when we still have the advantage of surprise?
区区一个汽车人怎么可能让我满足呢？
We must not allow our anger over the loss of Cliffjumper
飞过山牺牲了
to impair our judgement.
但不应让愤怒干扰我们的判断力
As of today, only we five Autobots remain on this earth.
时至今日 地球上只剩下我们五个汽车人了
We owe it to ourselves
我们要铭记塞博特恩的一切回忆
to the memory of Cybertron,
不仅为了自己 为了纪念塞博特恩
to any Autobots in any galaxy seeking safe harbour,
为了在各个星系寻找避难所的汽车人
to human kind.
也为了人类
And we owe it to the memory of our fallen comrade
更要为我们失去的战友
to survive.
而生存下去
Arcee?
阿尔茜？
If Cliff's gone, standing around here soaking won't bring him back.
小飞走了 站在这儿哭是不会让他复生的
So unless anyone minds,
如果你们没有意见
think I'll get back to protecting human kind.
我想我还是回去保护人类吧
Optimus, helping humans will only result in more tragedy.
擎天柱 帮助人类只会导致更多的悲剧
Your opinion is noted.
我明白你的意思
Welcome to KO drive-in, where every paddy is knockout.
欢迎光临KO快餐厅 每个肉饼都顶呱呱
May I take your order?
您想要点什么？
Two super combos, extra fries.
两份超级套餐 加量薯条
Ok, those numeral twos. Anything else?
好 2号套餐两份 还要点什么？
Yeah, some advice.
有 要些建议
How do I get an awesome job like yours?
怎么才能得到和你一样风光的工作？
So that's two "we're not as funny as we think we are" combos
您点的是两份“冷笑话”套餐
with the side of "bite me"!
赠一碟“有种就来啊”小菜！
5.59$, sir, at the window.
5.59美元 先生 窗口付款
I have to pay for that.
我…我要赔钱的
Twins.
虫兄鼠弟
Take five, Sadie.
休息一下 沙蒂
Hey, mom, I just got off.
嘿 妈妈 我刚下班
No, I'm not going to the dance.
不 我不去舞会了
Experience suggests I should never cut a rug.
经验告诉我 不能太出风头
Unless I'm stealing a carpet.
除非我真会跳舞
Be careful?
注意安全？
Seriously?
不是吧？
This is Jasper.
这儿可是贾斯帕
I love you.
我爱死你了
Yeah, I love you, too, mom. I got to run.
哦 我也爱你 妈妈 我得走了
Hello, beautiful.
你好啊 美人儿
Where've you been all my life?
怎么现在才出现？
Nice!
身材真好！
It may take a few KO pay checks,
KO餐厅的薪水实在不高
but I am gonna own a ride like you some day.
但总有一天 我要买辆和你一样的座驾
Are you talking to your motorcycle?
你在对你的摩托说话吗？
Yea, my motorcycle?
对…我的摩托？
No, I mean,
不 我是说
yes, yes,
对 对
it's... it's mine. But...
它…它是我的 但…
no, I'm not talking to...
不 我不是跟它说话…
Well, to you, I am.
是在跟你说话
How's things, Sierra?
还好吧 塞拉？
Take you for a spin sometime?
找时间带你去兜兜风如何？
Come on, smooth operator, wrap it up!
拜托 油嘴滑舌的家伙 该走了！
You... know my name?
你…知道我的名字？
We're in homeroom together.
我们一起在大教室听讲座
I'm Jack, Jack Darby.
我叫杰克 杰克・达比
Scrap.
糟了
Do not let go!
别放手！
Who said that?!
谁在说话？！
Commander Starscream, target sighted,
红蜘蛛指挥官 已发现目标
accompanied by a human youth.
有一名人类少年同行
Destroy them both!
把他们两个都干掉！
What... are you?
你…是什么？！
I don't exist.
我不存在
Tell anyone about me, and I will hunt you down.
如果你嘴巴不严 我一定不会放过你
Scrap!
糟了！
I don't even know her!
我根本不认识她！
Hop on!
上来！
Why are those guys shooting at us?
那帮人为什么开枪打我们？
There's no whys, kid,
没有原因 小鬼
and they're no guys.
他们也不是人类
Friend of yours?
你的朋友吗？
Family.
家人
Hi, mama.
嗨 妈妈
Racing.
赛车呢
Right up the street.
就在大街旁边
K. Just five more minutes.
好 再玩儿五分钟
You have no idea.
说了你也不懂
This ends here, Cons!
够了 虎子们！
What are they?
他们是什么？
Talking cars that turn into robots,
会说话的车变的机器人
or the other way around.
或者机器人变的车
This.... is... for... Cliff!
这是…为…了…飞过山！
No problem. Really.
没关系 真的
Leave him alone!
别碰他们！
Please...
求你了…
Bad call.
乌鸦嘴
Come on, come on!
快跑！快跑！
Don't look back!
别往后看！
What did we just see?
我们刚才看到什么了？
No idea, and I'm not sure I wanna find out.
不知道 而且我也不太想知道
Who's ready to rumble?
谁想干一仗？
What took you?
怎么这么久？
Traffic.
堵车
And the Cons would have been scrap-metal
如果不是被人类分了神
if I hadn't been distracted by the humen.
那对虎子早就成废铁了
Humen?
人类？
Two boys?
两个男孩？
I guess the second one caught us in action.
第二个可能是无意间看到我们变形的
I don't know, was a little busy at the time.
我也不知道 当时挺忙的
If the Decepticons are targeting us,
如果霸天虎想针对我们
anyone perceived as our ally will be at grave risk.
任何被视为与我们同盟的人 都会有生命危险
Raf, hey.
拉夫 嘿
Look, let's just...
这样吧
keep it between us and forget anything ever happened, ok?
我们对外守口如瓶 就当没这回事儿 好吗？
Jack!
杰克！
Oh, not again!
噢 又来了！
It... wants us to get in.
它…想让我们上车
No, just me.
不 就我一个
How do you know that?
你怎知道的？
It said so.
它就是这么说的
What?
什么？！
Yours is over there.
你的在那边
Look, I really don't think that...
可…我真的不认为…
How's it going?
还好吗？
Raf?
拉夫？
Wait, stop!
等等！停车！
Coolest... bike... ever.
有史以来…最酷的…摩托
Host parents?
寄宿监护人？
Ignore.
无视
Relax. I just wanna talk to you.
放松 我只想跟你谈谈
Don't you mean you and your new friend?
你和你的新朋友一起谈吗？
Kid, there's a lot you don't understand.
小鬼 有很多东西你不明白
No, I... I get it, I get it.
不 我…我明白 我明白
The first rule of robot fight club is
机器人搏击俱乐部的第一条规则就是
you don't talk about robot fight club.
不要谈论机器人搏击俱乐部
What YOU need to understand is
你要搞清楚的是
that I don't want a bunch of crazy talking vehicles
我不想有一堆会说话的疯车跟着我
following me around, trying to get me killed.
害我被人追杀
Look, Jack, is it?
这样 你叫杰克 是吧？
Your personal safety is exactly why Optimus Prime has requested your presence.
擎天柱要见你 正是为了你的人身安全考虑
Wait, eh... Optimus who?
擎天啥？
You maybe in danger
你可能有危险
because you are one of the few, one of the only who have ever seen us.
因为你是仅有的几个看到我们的人之一
Dude, what are you waiting for?
哥们儿 你还等什么？
Go with!
去嘛！
Scrap.
糟了
And why exactly are we taking her?
我们干嘛连她也带上？
Rules.
有规定
Hey, what... whoa!
嘿 什么…哇！
Cool...
酷！
I thought there were two.
不是只有两个吗
Haven't you heard?
你不知道吗？
Humans multiply.
人类可以繁殖
I'm Raf.
我叫拉夫
I'm Miko.
我叫神子
Who are you?
你叫什么？
Bulkhead.
隔板
Are you a car?
你是一辆车？
I bet you're a truck. A monster truck!
我敢说你是卡车 是大脚车！
Do you like heavy metal? How much do you weigh?
你喜欢重金属音乐吗？你多重？
Ever use a wrecking ball for a punching bag?
用破碎锤打过沙包吗？
So, if you guys are robots,
如果你们是机器人
who made you?
是谁造出你们的？
Please...
真要命…
We are autonomous robotic organisms from the planet Cybertron.
我们是来自塞博特恩星球的自主机械生命体
Also known as Autobots.
也可以叫我们“汽车人”
Why are you here?
你们为什么来地球？
To protect your planet from the Decepticons.
保护你们的星球免受霸天虎的侵害
The jokers who tried to bump us off last night.
就是昨晚那些想谋杀我们的喽
Okay...
好吧…
Why are they here?
那他们为什么来地球？
A fair question, Jack.
问得好 杰克
In part, they are here because our planet is uninhabitable,
部分原因是 我们的星球经过千百年的内战
ravaged by centuries of civil war.
已经不再适合居住
Why were you fighting a war?
你们干嘛要打仗？
Foremost,
原因有很多
over control of our world supply of energon,
核心问题 是为了我们的世界对于能量的控制权
the fuel and life blood of all Autobots and Decepticons alike.
也就是汽车人以及霸天虎的生命能量
The combat was fierce,
战斗非常激烈
and endured for centuries.
持续了数个世纪
In the beginning, I fought along side one whom I considered a brother.
起初 我和一个可与之称兄道弟的人并肩作战
But in war, ideals can be corrupted.
但是 战争可以将理想腐化
And it was thus,
正是这种腐化
that Megatron lost his way.
使威震天误入了歧途
Is there gonna be a quiz?
这是历史考试题吗？
So what does Megatron,
那个威震天…
or any of this,
还有这些事情
have to do with us?
跟我们有什么关系？
Megatron has not been seen or heard from in some time.
很久没有关于威震天的任何消息了
But if his return is imminent,
但如果他即将东山再起
as I fear, it could be catastrophic.
我恐怕 又要掀起一场腥风血雨
Those transmissions are emanating from deep space.
那些信号是从太空深处传来的
I would hate to waste the energon,
我可不想浪费能量
unless you're absolutely certain.
除非你对此十分肯定
Then lock on transmission coordinates
那么就锁定信号坐标
and activate the space bridge.
启动太空桥
Decepticons!
霸天虎们！
I have returned!
我回来了！